Guide to the Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004.
Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004
- Series III. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2005
  - Project Proposal: Today, Rubin, Ben, and Mark Hansen (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - DVD:
      - Listening Post, 2001-2002(documentation of installation)
      - Spin, 2002(documentation of installation)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Story Pipeline
      - Selected Works, 1993-2004
        overview of Rubin's work
      - Selected Research, 1991-2005
  - Project Proposal: The Analogous Landscape(includes floorplan of proposed installation, navigation instructions for CD and detailed information about each work sample on CD), Slayton, Joel (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - CD
      - (two powerpoint presentations: C5 (powerpoint presentation) (includes documentation of works C5, Lost Chihuahua, Panamint Launch at Lucky Jim Wash; Analogous Landscapes (powerpoint presentation) documents work in progress toward proposed project)
  - Project Proposal: MobBob, Stern, Eddo (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - DVD:
      - damaged disc; not in file(includes doc. of works Waco, 2004; Tekken Torture Tournament, 2001; Cockfight Arena, 2001; Sheik Attack, 2000; Vietnam Romance, 2003; Deathstar, 2003-4 )
  - Project Proposal: Emptiness Can Hold Things(includes installation plans and diagrams of proposed project and detailed descriptions of work samples), Strickland, Rachel (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - DVD:
      - ortable Effects: A Survey of Nomadic Design Practice, 1997(includes doc. of installation, "Exploratorium Exhibit")
      - Allons-y Alonzo: Souvenirs of a Landscape, 2000-2001(video assemblage/video documentary)
    - Slides
      - 13 Slides: doc of installations Portable Effects and Placeholder (1993)
  - Project Proposal: Latent Figure Protocol(includes diagrams and visualizations of proposed installation and detailed descriptions of videos and slides), Vanouse, Paul (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - VHS:
      - The Relative Velocity Device, 2002(6 min. doc of interactive installation)
      - Paradise Reconfigured, 2000(4 min doc of interactive installation)
      - Terminal Time, 2000(6 min clip of interactive cinema performance)
    - DVD:
      - Interactive Works by Paul Vanouse (1995-2003)(includes 2-6 minute video doc of Relative Velocity Inscription Device (interactive installation), 2002; PED (interactive installation), 2001; Paradise Reconfigured (interactive installation), 2002; Items 1-2000 (interactive installation), 1996; Follower (interactive installation), 1995; Terminal Time (interactive cinema), 1999-2000; Persistent Data Confidante (interactive database), 1997; Consensual Fantasy Engine (interactive cinema), 1995)
    - Slides
      - 8 Slides: includes doc of Items 1-2000 (interactive installation, 1996), Paradise Reconfigured (interactive installation, 2000), Cult of the New Eve (performance, 2000), and The Relative Velocity Inscription Device (interactive installation, 2002)
  - Project Proposal: Personal Zoo, Wight, Gail (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Rodentia Chamber Music (work in progress) and Rodentia Violincello (in progress; 2004)(mac OS preferred)
      - Kings Play Cards... (doc of software and installation), 2003(mac OS preferred)
      - Spike 1999
      - Cabinet of Curiosities: Meditations on Evolution, 2001(doc of installation)
      - Hereditary Allegories: A Study in Genetics (installation), 2003
    - DVD:
      - Rodentia Chamber Music(doc of installation)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Wight: www.notochord.org, 2004(offline version of artist's website)
      - Cabinet of Curiosities: Meditations on Evolution (software), 2001.
    - Catalogs
      - Gail Wight: The Evolution of Disarticulation, published by the San Francisco Art Institute in connection with the 2003 Adaline Kent Award Exhibition.(Includes essay, "Disheveled Neurochemistry: An Irreverent Reverence for Science," by Marcia Tanner.)
      - Gail Wight: "Spike"; Eduardo Kac "Genesis," published by the O.K. Centrum fur Gengenwartskunst, Oberösterreich, in connection with the Ars Electronica Exhibition "Cyberarts 1999"(Includes artist's statement about installation "Spike." In German and English.)
  - Project Proposal: Eliza Redux(includes instructions for viewing web-based work samples), Wortzel, Adrianne (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Eliza Redux, 2004
        interactive telerobotic website, in progress
    - CD-Rom:
      - Eliza Redux Web-Prototype(offline version of website www.elizaredux.org)
      - Wortzel: Application Documents Only(digital versions of application documents)
    - DVD:
      - Adrianne Wortzel Work Samples 2-7(includes 1-5 minutes clips of The Veils of Transferrence (video, in post-production), 2003-4; Camouflage Town (telerobotic installation), 2001; Sayonara Diorama (life and webcast web performance), 1998; Nomad is an Island (installation), 1997; Tableaux Vivant (installation), 1999; Anchorage (installation), 1997)
      - Work Sample 8: Adrienne Wortzel DVD 2 Veils of Transferrence (video), 2003-4()
    - Portfolio/Book
      - Works Publications Press.(Includes color images and criticism of previous works, catalog, Data Dynamics, from exhibit at Whitney Museum of Art March-June 2001, articles and press materials.)
  - Project Proposal: Memory Trace(includes floorplan of proposed installation), Z., Pamela (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - DVD:
      - Pamela Z Work Samples(includes 6-19 min. clips of: Voci (performance), 2003; Typewater (MetalVoice) (sound and video installation/performance), 2004)
    - CD
      - A Delay is Better, 2004(cd notes include detailed description of all tracks)
- Series IV. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2006
  - Project Proposal: Human Trials, Anstey, Josephine, and Dave Pape (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples (includes 2-8 minute clips of video doc of installations The Trial The Trail, The Thing Growing)
      - Supplemental Material (includes video doc of installations PAAPAB (Pick an Avatar, Pick a Beat) and Falling Over You)
  - Project Proposal: Computers are Cool Summer Tour 2k6, Arcangel, Cory (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - VHS:
      - I Heart Garfunkel(lecture/performance)
      - Super Mario Brothers(7-minute edit)
      - Supplemental Material(includes full 15-minute Super Mario Movie)
  - Project Proposal: Stream(ing), Barbier, Annette, and Drew Browning (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(includes video doc of installations Path of the Dragon and Wave Harmonies, and of performance River of Many Sides)
      - Supplemental Materials(includes video docs of two untitled installations) [missing]
  - Project Proposal: Rust Within Their Throats, Birchfield, David (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Documentation of installations Transition Soundings, Community Art and Interactions
  - Project Proposal: The Dubai Orlando Project, Blue, Carroll Parrott (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Book
      - The Dawn at my Back: Memoir of a Black Texas Upbringing
    - DVD-Rom
      - Search for Ibn Battuta Mall
      - The Dawn at My Back: Memoir of a Black Texas Upbringing
    - CD-Rom:
      - The Dawn at My Back Website
      - Dubai 2005
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://www.dawnatmyback.com
  - Project Proposal: Make Language, Böhlen, Marc (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - DVD:
      - The Universal Whistling Machine(9 minutes)
    - DVD-ROM
      - A Nature Interpretation Center With Second Thoughts(offline version of website by same title)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - A Nature Interpretation Center With Second Thoughts (UNSEEN)
  - Project Proposal: Wireless Public Space Interventions: WI-Fi Liberator, Brucker-Cohen, Jonah, and Katherine Moriwaki (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Website:Work Samples
      - http://www.undertheumbrella.net
      - http://www.scrapyardchallenge.com
    - DVD
      - JBC Interactive Projects(2 copies)
      - Supplemental Materials(Video and photo documentation of installations Tele-Tv, SearchEngine, LIveWindow, Cranks The Web, InternetRadio, Site-Traffic.net, IPO Madness, !Alerting INfastructure!, Mouse Miles, PoliceState, Scroller, Drawbot, Simple TEXT, and Phonetic Faces.)
    - CD-Rom:
      - JBC-KM Work Samples(2 copies)
  - Project Proposal: Notes for a Second Poem on the Third Worlds (Part 1), Bucher, Francois (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - DVD:
      - 2 DVDs (Not Received) (includes works Ernesto Samper Addresses Washington (2005), White Balance (to think is to forget difference) (2005), Television (an address), Tom Keenan, Live from New York (2003))
    - Print materials
      - “Television (An Address),” Journal of Visual Culture 4 (1): 5-15, 2005
  - Project Proposal: 200mm3, Canonge, Hector (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples: Software for web-based project Ciudad Transmobil, data collection project Integrated Urban Mappings, and new media performance Q'Doll Intervention
    - Print Materials
      - 7 pages visualizations of proposed project, color
  - Project Proposal: Remote Viewings, Cantanese, Paul (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - DVD:
      - DVD Portfolio(1-2 minute video documentation of online works Misplaced Reliquary, Collective Geology of Erased Space and Digital Cornell Boxes)
    - VHS:
      - VHS Portfolio(Video documentation of Super Ichthyologist Advance)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Misplaced Reliquary
      - Invisible Maps
      - Collective Geology of Erased Space
  - Project Proposal: Me Standing There, You Standing Here, Churi, Maya (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Forest Grove (2005)
      - Letters from Homeroom (2000)
  - Project Proposal: Food for Thoughts, Cornyn, Alison (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - DVD:
      - 360 Degrees.org
    - CD-Rom:
      - 360degrees.org: Perspectives on the CriminalJustice System (offline demo)
      - The Sonic Memorial Project
      - Food for Thoughts(2-minute demo)
    - VHS:
      - Supplementary Materials(Video documentation of installation)
      - I Wear Lucy
    - Booklet
      - 360Degrees.org
      - SonicMemorial.org
      - Food for Thoughts
      - I Wear Lucy
  - Project Proposal: Moving Tangents, Daggett, Mark (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Work Samples(for PC; 2 copies. Includes demos of artworks Carnivore is Sorry (2002), Balance Bar (2005), Browser Gestures (2001))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Carnivore is Sorry (browser, 2002)
  - Project Proposal: Companion Projects, Dobson, Kelly (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(Documentation of interactive sculptures ScreamBody, Blendie, and Machine Therapy.)
  - Project Proposal: :b.a.n.g* * lab, Dominguez, Ricardo (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - VHS:
      - Clip from documentary The Hacktivist
    - DVD:
      - Dolores From 10 to 22 hrs(documentation of live stream performance)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Work Samples
  - Project Proposal: Drawing Voices, Dongoski, Craig (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - VHS:
      - Video documentation of 6 clips of performances and sound experiments including Other Mind, Invisible Transmission, Drawing Voices, Metaphysical Poem, Signature, and Leviathan.
    - Slides
      - Supplemental Materials(10 slides documenting the exhibition of Other Mind drawings.)
    - Audio CD
      - Supplemental Materials(7 tracks of sound experiments)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Supplemental Materials(Examples of drawings from Other Mind experiments)
  - Project Proposal: Our Bodies, Dyson, Torkwase (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples (damaged, unplayable) (Stroll, Feels Like Yellow, Red Light, Green Light)
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples(Stroll, Feels Like Yellow, Red Light, Green Light(2 copies; Copy 2 includes documentation of installation Its About Small Things))
    - Slides
      - 4 slides documenting video and performance installation Its About Small Things
  - Project Proposal: Once a Wall,, or Ripple Remains, Even, Tirtza (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples(3-d animation demos of video installations Slip, Definition, and Icarus)
      - Supplemental Materials(Kayam Al Hurbano (Existing On Its Ruins))
      - Occupied Territory(demo of interactive video)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Local version of Occupied Territory website(http://www.occupied.org)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://www.occupied.org
    - Print Materials
      - photographic print floor plans and images of installations Slip, Definition, and Icarus
  - Project Proposal: Melodrama no. 13 (The Possibility of Failure), Flamini, Andrea (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - VHS:
      - 9-minute documentation of database narrative shortmovieaboutnothing (Melodrama No.12) outputted into video
    - CD-Rom:
      - local copy of online version of shortmovieaboutnothing (Melodrama No.12)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - shortmovieaboutnothing (Melodrama No. 12)
  - Project Proposal: Imaging Place: The U.S/Mexico Border, Freeman, John Craig (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(10 minute documentation of installation Imaging Place(2 copies))
      - Imaging Place(interactive demo)
    - Slides
      - 10 slides documenting installation Imaging Place
    - print:
      - Supplemental Materials(Compilation of press and promotional material for Imaging Place)
  - Project Proposal: Processing, Fry, Ben (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Ben Fry(includes demos of artworks Valence (1999) and Genome Valence (2002))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - isometricblocks (2004, 2005)
        [url not included in form]
  - Project Proposal: The Attachment Theories, Gilliam, Leah (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(Video channels from Agenda for a Landscape installation, Video clips from installation Apeshit v3)
      - Supplemental Materials(Four videos from installation Agenda for a Landscape, 4-5 minute video Playing the Race Card from exhibition Race in Digital Space, 3-minute excerpt from installation Apeshit v3)
    - Slides
      - 12 slides documenting installations Agenda for a Landscape and Apeshit v3
    - print:
      - promotional materials for Agenda for a Landscape and Apeshit v3
  - Project Proposal: The Tipping Point: Health Narratives from the South End, Hall, Jennifer (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Local copy of website for Coactive Installations
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Documentation for Coactive Sculptures
  - Project Proposal: The Endless Forest, Harvey, Auriea (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Endless Forest(demo video)
      - Endless Forest(software)
      - 8(demo video)
      - The Theater Gallery Tragedy(software demo)
    - Print Materials
      - Press review of online performance Wirefire, Tale of Tales, color screenshots and promotional material
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://tale-of-tales.com/TheEndlessForest
  - Project Proposal: I Needed to Know This, I Knew it was True, Hilton, Hope (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples(5 minute silent video In Search of Place)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Work Samples
        Mail art project
    - print:
      - This is the Future exhibition catalog, loose-leaf packet of reviews of artist's shows, 4 postcards
  - Project Proposal: The Parallel Series, Heaton, Kelly (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - DVD:
      - Kelly Heaton Sample(includes video of projects Reflection Loop (2000-2001), Live Pelt (2000-2003), The Parallel Series (proposed), Dead Pelt (2002))
    - CD-Rom:
      - Kelly Heaton Supplemental(includes documentation of 1998-2000 projects The Physical Pixel Project, Nami, The Digital Palette, The Sensor Camera, Aesthetic Computation)
    - Print Materials
      - 4 color promo cards
      - photocopies of articles
  - Project Proposal: POF-TTNO6, Huang Shih Chieh (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - VHS Tape
      - Shih Chieh Huang Sample Work(includes clips of artworks F0101 (1998-2002), Apple Project (2002), FM-TT-03 (2003), “DeResFX.kill (karmaphysics 5.0amp);” (2003), PC-102 (Looking In, Lower Manhattan Cultural Council) (2002), Organic Concept- NYP (2004), Ki-Ki-Ko-Ko (2004))
    - Print Materials
      - photocopies of press coverage, in English and Chinese, and b/w and color visualizations of proposed project
  - Project Proposal: Pulse, Jevbratt, Lisa (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - CD
      - Work Samples(Still images from interactive website Infome Imager) Still images from interactive website 1:1(2) and Migration Still images from interactive website The Voice
    - print:
      - Photocopied exhibition catalog net.art 2.0
      - Photocopied article s from publications artphoto, Digital Art and Internet Art
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Work Samples
        Infome Imager
  - Project Proposal: Playground, Kaiser, Paul, and Shelley Eshkar (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - DVD:
      - Video footage from installation Pedestrian, imagery generated from performance 22, imagery generated from performance how long does the subject linger at the edge of the volume... (2 discs)
    - Print:
      - Color prints of installation diagrams for Arrival, BIPED, Pedestrian, how long does the subject linger..., and Immateriall/Ultramaterial, photocopies of press materials
  - Project Proposal: Healing Pool, Knep, Brian (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(2-5 minute video documentation of installations Healing Series, Flower (Umbilicus), and Drift Grid/I)
  - Project Proposal:, Kurtz, Steve (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Website:Work Samples:
      - The Cult of the New Eve
      - Molecular Invasion
      - Free Range Grains
  - Project Proposal: Eye Contact Systems (includes color visualization of referenced projects), Levin, Golan (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples(Documentation of performances/installationss Messa di Voce, Dialtones: A Telesymphony, Interactive Bar Tables, The Manual Input Sessions, RE-MARK and Hidden Worlds of Noise and Voice)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(Documentation of performances/installationss Messa di Voce, Dialtones: A Telesymphony, Interactive Bar Tables, The Manual Input Sessions, and RE-MARK)
      - Active Score Music(includes documentation of Scribble and Small Fish Tale)
    - Audio CD
      - Dialtones: A Telesymphony(complete version)
  - Project Proposal: Watching: Camera: Movies, Neumann, Andrew (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - VHS Tape:
      - Andrew Neumann Work Sample(includes documentation of Industrial Wall Panels, Wall Constructions, and Video Projections)
  - Project Proposal: Online Journey to Mictlan, Newman, Joaquin Alejandro (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Work Samples
      - Online Journey to Mictlan
  - Project Proposal: CLASS: C’s VANCADE, Ochoa, Ruben (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - DVD:
      - Ruben Ochoa 2006 Fellow 1 of 2 (Ruben)(slideshow of images documenting the artist’s recent performances)
      - Ruben Ochoa 2006 Fellow 2 of 2 (VANCADE)(video documentation of proejct Vancade)
    - Print Materials:
      - photocopies of reviews (14 pages), color prints of images from Vancade project
  - Project Proposal: Electronic Quilting Bee, Pearce, Celia (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - CD-ROM:
      - 3 untitled video samples(unclear format; sample work form not received)
    - Print
      - Work Samples(Celia Pearce: Selected Works (booklet of text and photographs of selected works) Ludica: Selected Projects (booklet of text and photographs from Ludica women's game art collective)
  - Project Proposal: BioLab-1, Pell, Richard (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - DVD:
      - Institute for Applied Autonomy: Bridging the Gap(includes documentation of projects Contestational Robotics, iSee, and TXTmob)
    - Print Materials:
      - photocopies of press reviews and reports (13 pages)
  - Project Proposal: Breakfast Club, Pfeiffer, Paul (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - DVD:
      - Compilation(includes samples of video works Orpheus Descending (2000/2001), Dutch Interior (2001), Morning After the Deluge (2003), Empire (2004)) [not received])
    - Print Materials:
      - printouts from website of C-Cubed, communications outsourcing company (3 p., color)
    - Catalogs:
      - Paul Pfeiffer: Orpheus Descending, New York Public Art Fund: 2001.
      - Paul Pfeiffer at the Athens Municipal Cultural Center “Melina”, 2003
      - Paul Pfeiffer, Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago, 2003
      - Paul Peiffer, Hatje Cantz, 2004
  - Project Proposal: Event Map, Phillips, Jon (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Website:Work Samples:
      - Inkscape: Open Soure Drawing Application and Open Source Community
        (Online demo of software)
      - Open Clip Art Library: Public Domain User-submitted Clip Art Collection
      - ccHost: Web Software to Support Collaborating, Sharing and Storing of Multi-media
    - Website:Supplemental Material:
      - Event Map Presentation Website
  - Project Proposal: Wind Window One, Raaf, Sabrina (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(Video documentation of 5 installations Translator II, searchstoretrash, Lost, Breath (IV) The Unstoppable Hum, Dry Translator, and Saturday.)
    - Slides:
      - 20 slides; documentation of installations on DVD
    - Print:
      - Catalog, Here and Now, promotional materials for exhibitions The E-show, Sense Data,Moving Parts, The Test People, photocopies of articles and reviews, glossy prints of proposed installation
  - Project Proposal: Birth of a Nation (War of the Worlds), Ralske, Kurt (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples(Video documentation of installations MoMA Display Screens and Elektropoesia, Excerpt from video Darkness (Not Darkness))
  - Project Proposal: The hymNext Designer Hymen Project, Reodica, Julia (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - CD:
      - Work Samples(Still images from Live Organism Care, The Workhorse Zoo, and hymNext)
    - Audio CD:
      - Radio Netherlands: Interview on the hymNext Project
  - Project Proposal: Choose Your Own Conversation (CYCOC), Sarff, Michael, and Tim Whidden (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Work Samples(Endnode (aka Printer Tree), Five Small Videos about Interruption and Disappearing, Website Unseen #01, Random Access Mortality, Quicktime movie 1 year Performance Video (aka sma HsiehUpdate), Quicktime documentation of performance Karaoke Death Match 100 (2 copies))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Website Unseen #01, Random Access Mortality
  - Project Proposal: Threatbox.us, Sester, Marie (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - VHS:
      - Documentation of installations ACCESS, BE[AM](2 copies)
    - DVD:
      - Documentation of installations ACCESS, BE[AM](2 copies)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Local Websites(local copy of website ACCESS)
    - Slides:
      - 10 slides; still image documentation of installations ACCESS, BE[AM]
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - ACCESS
  - Project Proposal:, Simon, John F. Jr. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - DVD:
      - 2006 Sample Work(includes documentation of software artworks Endless Victory and aLife)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Mobility Agents((writings and drawings, electronic book and drawing program, includes CD booket))
  - Project Proposal: Windfall(includes 4 color visualizations of wind turbines), Singer, Brooke (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Print Material:
      - Sample Work(hard copy version of artist’s online portfolio; includes descriptions and color documentation of artworks Swipe (2002-), Moport (2004-), and Zapped! (2004-))
      - How to Become a Zapped! RFID Scout: Stop the Creep!(Informational workbook on RFID, published by Preemptive Media)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Swipe
      - Moport
      - Zapped!
      - Sample Work